I will talk a bit about what Telecomix really is,
... generally, and so...
This is our logo.
There is some symbolism in it,
but there is quite a lot.
We have written about it on Wikipedia.
My name is Elis, I live in Stockholm,
I have ham radio signal SA0BSE.
I am an operator on Telecomix IRC.
Telecomix has been nicknamed quite
a lot during the years,
"Socio-cybernetic jellyfish cluster" being one
of the most tenacious attibutions we've had,
"True Internet Heroes" was used this spring
when I was in Brussels.
I had my laptop under my arm when a guy
came up to me and said:
It was kind of a "wow"-feeling,
"Telecommunist Cluster" we have seen
recently in online articles.
We have made some fun about communism and so on
Tech Support for North Africa.
There has been some cases during the spring -
- that most of you have probably heard about.
What is Telecomix? That's a difficult question -
- and there is no definitive answer.
We have an IRC network.
It is often looked upon as a meeting spot -
- where people with shared interests
meet to talk, have fun, and -
- do different things if they feel like it.
Projects are often initiated -
- with different goals for different cases.
I will talk about the different projects in a bit.
Eh, mac keyboard. Jellyfish - we use it quite often
They swim in clusters -
- and follow each other.
They are generally fine.
Power of Adhocracy, that is the
name of the conference.
We have even called it do-ocracy a bit.
Those who do, do.
Those who want to do stuff start projects
and start working toward change.
Because they feel like it.
Most Telecomix business is done
because people think it is fun.
There is not a lot of incentive otherwise.
These are the three steps through which
Telecomix projects are usually started.
People are hanging on our channel. Something that
we don't like comes in; stuff that we want to fix.
- and then we will start a project for it.
One example is the Egypt project -
- that became rather large.
There has been a lot of other projects.
It works, too! Much more efficiently than
I thought in the beginning.
People like doing stuff as long as we make sure it's fun.
As long as it's nice there will always be a driving force.
Here are some examples of stuff we've done.
Telecomix has done some lobby work
in EU and Sweden during the years -
together with French and German groups.
We have been mailing and talking to politicians, -
- answer to department referrals, sending in paper, -
and a lot of stuff like that.
Last year in December I and few others
in the audience did a lot of Wikileaks mirroring.
Then we have the Egypt project -
- that became pretty big and known -
- where we helped to set up internet in Egypt.
And a lot of other stuff in that area.
The Syria project is going on right now.
I will get around to that, too.
Wikileaks mirroring.
December 3rd I woke up to the message
"Wikileaks is down".
We started to investigate it and discovered
that the DNS were being DDoSed.
So you could not resolve the  servers.
After some Twitter work and looking around online -
- we found a computer that had its Cablegate archive.
We mirrored it -
- and talked about it on the Internet
"Here's a copy of everything" -
- use this one. Copy it too, if you like.
That evening like 57 mirrors had emerged,
depending on how you look at it.
This was a Friday.
During the weekend Wikileaks presented
its mass-mirroring project, -
to auto-mirror and auto-update mirrors.
Toward the end of next week there were
over 2000 mirrors.
It is difficult to name them all here.
That was a quite exciting project, -
and during that project we found that
it wasn't only the mirroring that was the issue.
There were some cases about bad
behavior from among others Paypal.
Like, freezing the account.
There were several others doing things like that.
Flattr were the only ones who stood strong -
- during that period, and they have
even continued doing that afterwards.
I have a nice picture from this winter.
It hasn't really been documented like
that, but it is cute nonetheless.
I don't think it'll look like that om 50 years,
but it's cool still.
Egypt. Yeah, we had a number of projects.
This is definitely not a complete list.
But I thought I should talk a bit about them.
The modem project. We set up modem pools.
We did that by talking to ISP and administer
the handling of the phone numbers, -
- and to get them down to Egypt
in various different ways.
That took a lot of administration to do, -
- but our lines were crammed, constantly.
They were rung down.
There is no way to 100% verify that
everything came from Egypt, but -
- we can assume a large part of it did.
That's the impression we got from the
people we talked to, at least.
I started an amateur radio project
where we tried to set up listening posts
on the amateur radio band.
On specific frequencies that are
often used in the ham radio community.
Then we went on to stream out
everything that was sent on those bands -
- that reached our stations via internet and web radio.
We had around 100-200 listeners, -
who listened to static for hours
during the period, -
- in the hopes that they would catch
some telegraphy.
We got one telegraphy, actually.
Although not so much, -
- and we could not verify its origin.
The biggest problem we
had with that project was that -
- there exists only 140 radio
amateurs in total in Egypt.
It is a very small number, and all
of them turned out to be educated by the army.
So I don't think that group of people -
is the group that will broadcast on SOS
frequencies needing help, -
- when they are presumably
working for the army.
But it was a very exciting project.
We repolished an old tech -
and showed that it still
exists and is usable.
It is out of band communication, and it is
something that is always nice to be able to use.
The fax project.
It was pretty much done with Google.
Finding fax numbers in Egypt -
- and then fax information flyers to all
faxes in the entire country.
We did that. It seemed that most of it
arrived. Some of it probably disappeared.
We don't know if we found all the fax numbers, -
that's a lot of guesswork, basically.
But it's also an interesting project about
stuff that is actually possible to do, -
- without even leaving one's apartment.
IP Scan project.
We had three persons scanning the
entire Egyptian IP range, -
- for addresses that were up and active, -
- and then we did a port scan over
all the addresses that were up, -
and sent forged HTTP requests to all
webservers throughout the nation -
- that contained messages in its request
header instead of POST or GET.
Like, "we have modem pools"
- and that kind of messages.
This was a project that took a lot of time, -
- and those who worked on it were very
skilled. I was not one of them.
This was a rather successful project, because -
- the Egyptians hadn't shut down their
entire internet, just parts of it.
So it worked rather well.
Egypt had shut down the internet for
the majority of the population, -
- but they hadn't shut down the internet
for 5-star hotels or companies.
Basically so they wouldn't affect
businesses too much.
But it turned out to be cumbersome
for them in the end.
When people exploited the holes that were.
Since then, in Sweden we have done
a lot of work to talk with news stations, -
to have them report on the news
that we have received.
We had some intensive weeks when
we were on TV on a number of occasions, -
both on SVT, ABC nyheterne and Rapport.
Different parts of Telecomix were present.
We talked about stuff that was happening
and what we had done, -
- and what we would continue to do.
Then we worked a lot with these four
information channels -
- distributing information, in order
to get information down to Egypt.
First aid information; all sorts of info
that is usable in hectic situations.
From what we have heard, people were
benefiting. But you never really know for sure.
Anyone can come forth and say stuff.
Syria... It is active right now, -
I won't say a lot about that.
There was a lot of BlueCoat logs the
other week. 54 gigs or something, -
I haven't been involved in the
Syria project myself, -
- there have been other people
working on that.
Telecomix is a lot about "those wo do
are the ones that lead."
And I haven't done anything
in that project, so...
Not my project.
But they seem to be very skilled
at what they're doing.
It is going to be interesting for both me
and probably many of you -
- to see how it goes for them.
It's a promising project, -
- and no one knows how
it is going to work out.
Then, we have not only done large things,
we have also worked with smaller projects.
Telecomix isn't all about big projects
and huge workloads and big things, -
- it needs to be fun. If it isn't fun,
then nobody is going to work on it.
The driving force is that is has to be fun,
and that others can benefit from it.
We're running our chat network.
We think it is nice to talk there, -
- uncontrolled, of course.
And we have a Jabber server.
Lots of small projects.
Then we have the DNS project, which
also is very interesting.
But I don't know how many people are
working on it right now.
It's not my project either.
Telecomix is very divided in terms of what
projects individual people devote their time to.
Everybody is definitely not
involved in everything.
That would be quite a lot of work
for that one person.
But that's how it works anyway, -
Those who can their parts talk about their parts.
I have, for example, done everything
concerning the stickers -
- that we have distributed today.
I started with this last spring, -
and those that have been given out
today are generation three.
And... Yeah, they have improved.
Some links: Telecomix chat, wiki, -
and then a little about me and who I am.
If anybody has questions after the talk,
go there to find contact information for me.
Then there is always the chat. It is basically
active every hour of the day.
Everybody is welcome there. It's a cool
place to hang. I can recommend it.
Questions?
We never succeeded in finding out
who DDoSed Wikileaks.
There was some suspicion, but we
could never determine it for sure.
Our involvement was mostly in
mirroring the stuff,
and then it ended up being so big
that it couldn't be taken down.
The logo? Yeah, we can say a lot about that.
Whoops, we looped.
We have Omega, that's about resistance.
Ohms law, that is well-known for many.
Internet activism is very much about
resistance towards the rest of the community.
We want to change, so we are
resistant towards stuff thats happening.
The lightnings are from the old Televerket
[telecommunications company]
There was some people asking
about that outside, too.
The pyramid... Illuminati as we
say. Pyramids are nice.
I haven't seen anything about Illuminati
in any Telecomix business.
And the star; that is communism. That
can also be fine sometimes.
It is more about being fun than
being serious, -
- according to me.
Any more questions?
None?
Then I suppose we can end this...
Well, people can ask me after
the talk. I will be here all night.
Then I'm also on IRC. Telecomix IRC.